MD FATHIR AHMED SHISHIR

Software Engineer

@ mfa.shishir@gmail.com# fathir-portfolio.netlify.app

(+49) 015752125266 fathir-ahmed

Frankfurt am main, Germany Fathir-shishir



CAREER OBJECTIVE

Computer Science and Engineering graduate with more than 1 year of experience in web-based systems development. Seeking to move into new engineering position in a high throughput development team where i can take new challenges and excel my knowledge.

Exploring segments of backend development and modern frameworks. Ultimate goal is to explore myself fully and improve skill to work as a key player in a challenging and creative environment.

EXPERIENCE

Web Developer

Upscale IT Solution - UIS

August 2018 - August 2019

Dhaka

- Developed custom API layer to handle all CRUD transactions, JWT token management and implemented interceptors to embed custom headers.
- Maintained high-level expertise in React sate management strategies including context API, Redux, Redux-saga.
- Created reusable UI components using React with JavaScript.
- Optimized applications for maximum speed and scalability.

Analyst

Quantanite

Nov 2019 - May 2021

London

- Built a webapp to filter and Highlight expected keywords from the unsorted data.
- Content moderation, Data labeling and Annotation
- Use and understanding of JIRA Issue Tracker

EDUCATION

M.S. in Information Technology

Frankfurt University of Applied Sciences

Oct 2020 - Current

Frankfurt

Courses: Software Engineering with ASP.Net Core, Cloud Computing, Machine Learning, Mobile Computing etc.

B.S. in Computer Science and Engineering

Daffodil International University

April 2015 - April 2019

Dhaka

PROJECTS

Doctors Portal-Doctor's appointment booking

Website Link ⟨/> GitHub Link (Client) GitHub Link (Server)

- A web application of Taking appointments on their selected date from the calendar using React-Day-Picker
- Dashboard for admin and users. Handled application state management using Context-api and Custom Hook and routing with React-router-dom.
- Login, Registration with google.used Firebase for authentication and JWT for authorization and form is controlled by Reacthook-form.
- Add and remove doctors. CRUD API written in ExpressJS and saved data to MongoDB

Technology Used: Node Js, Express Js, JWT, Mongodb, Nodemailer, Stripe, React, React-query, React-hook-form, React-router-dom, Firebase, Tailwindcss, Daisyui.

Love TO Travel-Travel Blog Website

Website Link ⟨→ GitHub Link (Client) GitHub Link (Server)

- A web application where users can Post, Update and Delete blog.CRUD API written in ExpressJS and saved data to MongoDB
- Used disgus where users can express their reaction on blogs.
- Search blog and show related blog based on tag and title.
- Handled application state management using Redux and routing with React router and Axios for network requests.

Technology Used: NodeJS, Express JS, JWT, Mongoose, React, Redux toolkit, React-redux, Material-ui

Get Gears-Manufacturer Website

Website Link ⟨/> GitHub Link (Client) GitHub Link (Server)

- Showing the different types of Parts, Our Business Summary, Customer Review
- Dashboard for admin and users, used Nested route with useEffect dependency Injection
- Login, Registration with google.used Firebase for authentication and JWT for authorization and form is controlled by Reacthook-form.

Technology Used: Node JS, Express JS, Mongodb, React, React-hook-form, React-router-dom, Firebase, Tailwind, DaisyUi

Fit-X

Features: React single page application.

Technology Used: HTML, SCSS, Bootstrap, React, React-router

SKILLS



PROJECT MANAGEMENT

Git Docker JIRA

LANGUAGES

Bangla English German



COURSES



Complete Web Development Course

MERN Stack Web Development Course by Jhankar Mahbub

Credential Link